Alexandre DuBreuil

Software Developer

Paris, France – Montreal, Canada

a +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
c) github.com/dubreuia
y twitter.com/dubreuia
□ alexandredubreuil.com
□ contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Summary

Software developer with 10 years of experience, as a freelancer, technical lead, and architect. Experience in full stack web development, DevOps, software factory automation, and application security. Also book author, open source maintainer, conference speaker, and trainer for web developers. Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript

DevOps: git, Maven, Ansible, Jenkins, Docker

Culture: Linux, Open Source, Continuous Delivery, DevOps

Security: Threat modeling, Hashicorp Vault

Methodology: Kanban, Agile

Experience

Web Development Trainer

DuBreuil Consulting (Simplon.co)

Trainer on web languages and technologies for full stack web developers (see recorded classes).

(January 2020 - May 2020) 4 months

Paris, France

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \it Technologies: & \sf Java, & \sf JavaScript, & \sf Spring Boot, & \sf Angular, \\ \tt UML, TDD & \end{tabular}$

Generative Music Composer

DuBreuil Consulting (DreamBank)

Composer of generative music, for the DreamBank art exhibit of Claire Malrieux, using machine learning and Magenta (see technical content).

(July 2019 - December 2019) 6 months

Paris, France

Technologies: Python, Magenta, Tensorflow, Ableton Live, Machine Learning, Generative Music

Security Consultant

DuBreuil Consulting (LesFurets)

Security architecture on secrets management with Hashicorp Vault for passwords (see technical content).

(April 2019 - June 2019) 3 months

Paris, France

Technologies: Java, Bash, Ansible, Hashicorp Vault

Software Architect

LesFurets.com

(June 2016 - October 2018) 2.5 years

Paris, France

Software architect on a 500,000 lines web application, working on full stack refactoring, domain driven design, infrastructure automation, software factory, continuous delivery and devops tooling.

• Refactoring of the legacy insurance product domain

model code and the insurance validation rules in dOOv.

 Modernizing of the infrastructure automation with Ansible and Docker.

Technologies: Java, Docker, Ansible, Hashicorp Vault Culture: Domain Driven Design, DevOps, TDD

Technical Lead

LesFurets.com

(January 2014 - June 2016) 2.5 years

Paris, France

Technical leader of an Agile team of 5 developers responsible for the 60 web services communicating with the insurers, providing agile management, mentoring, architecture design, software development and software craftsmanship.

- Team management on the Kanban methodology, with visual management, daily stand ups, weekly One-on-One with team members.
- Team mentoring on code review and code quality, as well as pair programming.
- \bullet Development and architecture of services in $\mathsf{Java},$ as REST and WSDL web services.
- Continuous delivery with Jenkins and Maven.
 Technologies: Java, Maven, Jenkins, REST, WSDL
 Culture: Kanban, Visual management, Daily stand-ups,
 One-on-One

Alexandre DuBreuil

Software Developer

Paris, France - Montreal, Canada

a +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
c) github.com/dubreuia
y twitter.com/dubreuia
□ alexandredubreuil.com
□ contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Java EE Consultant

(January 2010 - August 2013) 3.5 years

CGI France

Paris, France

Java EE consultant on a large scale front office and back office Java application in the energy business (3,000,000 lines of code). Development, testing, delivery, training and documentation.

- Development of front-end in JSP, backend in Java and data layer in SQL.
- Development of multi-threaded algorithms, handling large datasets (1,000+ curves, millions of points) ef-
- ficiently, for the energy market on price optimisation and energy curve manipulation.
- Development of a JavaScript curve visualisation component used to visualise energy curves and apply operations on them.

Technologies: Java EE, JSP, Maven, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery, jQPlot

Publications & Conferences

Hands-On Music Generation with Magenta

(June 2019 - January 2020) 8 months

Book published on Packt Publishing. Explore the role of deep learning in music generation and assisted music composition.

Tags: Python, Magenta, Tensorflow, Machine Learning, Generative Music, Ableton Live

Music Generation with Magenta: Using Machine Learning in Arts

Conference on leveraging machine learning technologies for music generation using Magenta.

Conferences: Devoxx Belgium 2019, IRCAM Paris 2020 Tags: Python, Magenta, Tensorflow, Machine Learning, Generative Music, Ableton Live

Hashicorp Vault and Continuous Delivery

Conference on securing your application secrets with infrastructure automation, continuous delivery and Hashicorp Vault.

Conferences: Devoxx UK 2020, Devoxx France 2019, JUG Nantes 2019

Tags: Hashicorp Vault, Continuous Delivery, DevOps

Domain Object Oriented Validation (dOOv)

Conference on dOOv, a fluent API for type-safe domain model validation and mapping (see Project – Domain Object Oriented Validation).

Conferences: JDK IO Copenhagen 2018, Snowcamp 2018, Softshake Geneva 2017

Tags: dOOv, Java, Domain Driven Design

Apache Spark for Java Developers

Conference on using Apache Spark with Java.

Breizhcamp Rennes 2017, Snowcamp Grenoble 2017

Conferences: Softshake Geneva 2017, Devoxx Krakow 2017,

Tags: Java, Apache Spark, Big Data

Continuous Merge with git-octopus

Conference on shipping code to production everyday in a feature branching environment with git-octopus.

Conferences: Open RDay Paris 2017, JUG Marseille 2016, JUG Tours 2016, AgileTour Rennes 2014

Tags: git, DevOps, Continuous delivery

Alexandre DuBreuil

Software Developer

Paris, France - Montreal, Canada

a +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
c github.com/dubreuia
y twitter.com/dubreuia
alexandredubreuil.com
contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Projects

Intellij Save Action Plugin ★382

(January 2015 - today) 5 years

Creator and maintainer of an Intellij plugin that adds save actions to the IDE. Five stars rating on the JetBrains plugin website and 75,000 unique downloads per version. Tags: Java, Intellij

Domain Object Oriented Validation (dOOv) ★50 (September 2017 - September 2019) 2 years

Creator, maintainer and evangelist on dOOv, a fluent API for type-safe bean validation and mapping. *Tags:* Java, Domain Driven Design

Project git-octopus ★193

(November 2014 - June 2017) 3.5 years

Evangelist and committer on git-octopus, a tool enabling the continuous merge workflow. Tags: git

Education

Pierre and Marie Curie University (Paris VI)

(September 2009 - January 2010) 4 months

Computer Science Master - International exchange - CREPUQ

Paris, France

International exchange student from University of Montreal.

University of Montreal

(September 2007 - January 2011) 4 years

Computer Science Baccalaureate

Montreal, Quebec

Program with 1 semester of international exchange and 3 internships of 4 months

- CGI Paris internship Java backend development (see experience).
- CGI Montreal internship Java full stack web development with Hibernate for an internal application.
- CHUM Montreal internship Java full stack web development for an internal application.

Jean-de-Brebeuf College

(September 2005 - June 2007) 2 years

DEC in science, letters and arts

Montreal, Quebec

Interests

Big music geek, listen at alexandredubreuil.com/music, also

Sports cycling, squash, climbing

Geek mechanical keyboards, gaming, vim

Music modular synthesizer, music production, DJ